Guide to the Native American Educational Services Press Records 1955-1994
University of Chicago Library
Native American Educational Services Press. Records
1955-1994
3 linear feet (6 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
This collection contains manuscripts and proofs of publications of the NAES College Press. The collection forms part of the archives of Native American Educational Services, and is particularly strong in materials related to Sol Tax and Robert Thomas.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
Established in Chicago in 1974, NAES College (Native American Educational Service) aimed to improve the leadership of Native communities and to ensure that tribal knowledge, traditions and values play a major role in the higher education of Native students. Before closing its doors in 2007, NAES College offered a single degree, a Bachelor's of Arts in General Studies with an emphasis in Public Policy, and tribal knowledge, community service, community development and leadership.
Scope Note
This collection contains manuscripts and proofs of publications of the NAES College Press. It includes many materials related to Sol Tax and Robert Thomas, including a typescript for Sol Tax’s “The World View of Panajachel: A Guatemalan Indian Ethnography.”
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
NAES College; Indians of North America; Indians of North America -- Education (Higher); Indian universities and colleges -- United States
INVENTORY
- A Documentary History of the Fox Project, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fox Project, republication materials, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miller, Jay, Delaware Integrity, manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Documentary History of the Fox Project, original stencils of 1st version, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Documentary History of the Fox Project, original stencils of 1st version, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Beck, David, correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Office files, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Publications, The Journal of Applied Behavioral Science, Volume 12, Number 3, 1976 Toward Economic Development for Native American Communities, 1969 The University of Chicago Round Table, 1969 Ethnohistory, Winter-Spring, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Thomas, Robert, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Thomas, Robert, "Process and Identity," 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Thomas, Robert, "Impediments to Analysis," 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Thomas, Robert, "The New Sacred Nationalism," undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Tax, Sol, and Robert Thomas, "Education ‘For’ American Indians: Threat or Promise?" 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Thomas, Robert, correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Untitled manuscript, regarding "Indian prophecy," undated (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
- Thomas, Robert,, Cherokee Prophecy Proofs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Thomas, Robert, Articles, 1985-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Thomas, Robert, correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Thomas, Robert, correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Typographic Resource Center Correspondence, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "American Indian Education in the Chicago Public Schools" Cover Mock-Up, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Banai, Eddie, "Generation to Generation" manuscript, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Education Report Mailing List, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- NEH "Publication Subvention," 1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Fox Project Schedule, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "Native Voices in the City: The Chicago American Indian Oral History Project" Manuscript, Folder 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "Native Voices in the City: The Chicago American Indian Oral History Project" Manuscript, Folder 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "American Indian Education in the Chicago Public Schools" Manuscripts, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "American Indian Education in the Chicago Public Schools" Publication Materials, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Cherokee Prophecy, manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Cherokee Prophecy, manuscript, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Cherokee Prophecy, manuscript, initial submission to NAES Press, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
- Fogel, Robert, Comments on Cherokee Prophecy, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Tax, Sol, "The World View of Panajachel: A Guatemalan Indian Ethnography" Manuscript, 1978-1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Tax, Sol, "The World View of Panajachel: A Guatemalan Indian Ethnography" Manuscript, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Tax, Sol, "The World View of Panajachel: A Guatemalan Indian Ethnography" Manuscript, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
- Cherokee Prophecy Proofs and Manuscripts, undated (Box 6, Folder 4-6)